（キラービー）九尾のガキ。
Hey, Nine Tails' brat,
thanks for trying to save Motoi.
モトイを助けようとしてくれて
センキュー。
（ナルト）おう！　ヘヘヘ！
Sure.
（モトイ）ナルトは不思議と
人を引きつける何かがある。
Naruto has the ability to
bring people together.
それは　ビーさんと同じだな。
Just like Bee.
（ヤマト）そんな感じがします。　はい。
Yes! I totally agree!
お前のことは
もう一度　再考！
I think I need to
reconsider ya mate.
お前　なかなかいいヤツ
最高！
You're quite a good guy,
real top rate.
タコのおっさん　イカすぜラップ！
Octopops,
ya got the best rap...
会えてよかった　ホントにラッキー！
I'm so happy to know ya,
I'm one lucky chap!
《ナルトに　ビーさんと同じところが
あるのはいいが→
It's great that Naruto and
Bee share similar traits.
正直　ラップまで
マネされんのはイヤだな》
But frankly, I wish he'd stop
copying his rapping.
ヨー！　ビートかませ！
Yo! Keep the beat.
ん？
((テメエにビーさんの何がわかる！？
What do you know about Bee?
(それ以上　グダグダ言ってたら
俺が許さねえぞ　ガキ！))
If you keep complaining about him,
I won't forgive you, kid!
《タコのおっさん→
Motoi trusts Octopops.
モトイのおっちゃんに
信頼されてるし》
Did that happen?
((そんなことあったっけか？))
《タコのおっさんも
モトイのおっちゃんを信頼してる》
And Octopops trusts Motoi.
ヨー！　俺は　ナルトだってばよ！
ヘヘヘ！
Yo! I'm Naruto, ya know!
《よし　決めた！》
All right, it's decided!
ったく！
てばよ　てばよ　ってヨー。
Man, it's "ya know, ya know"
all the time.
うるせぇってばヨー！
Shuddup, ya know!
ヘッ！
真実の滝へ行け。
今のお前ならイケイケだ。
Go to the Waterfall of Truth.
You'll pass with flying colors now.
フフフ。
ibitsu na merodll de dekita aisareru beki ikimono da
Made from a distorted melody,
I'm a creature that should be loved
seika wa agerarenakute mo kokoro ga utatte iru kara
Even if I can't better myself,
I'll continue to sing from my heart
dore dake tsuyoi ame koete aisareru beki ikimono ka?
What storms must I overcome
To be a creature who should be loved?
yakusoku ga mamorenakute mo kokoro wa utatte iru kedo
Even if you can't keep your promise
My heart will keep on singing, but...
dono doa nokku shite aketara ii?
Which door should I knock on and open?
aketara doko e mukattara ii?
Once I open it, where should I go?
hitori ja kaerenai kara
I can't go home by myself
dareka o matte ita dake
I was just waiting for someone
kimi ga ima ichiban aitai hito wa dare?
Who is the one you want to meet the most?
kokoro no naka de dake hanaseru hito no kazu wa fuete iku
The number of people that I can only speak to in my heart
keep increasing
dakara tsuyoku naritakatta tada
So I just wanted to be strong
bokura mada yomitarinai monogatari
Our story just hasn't been told enough
muriyari owarenai koto wakattete
We know it's not something we can just quit
dare mo mina jibun no mama
Because we all want to be ourselves
tsuyoku naritakatta kara
We wanted to be strong
The Next Challenge! Naruto vs. Nine Tails!
懲りずに　また来たか。
So have you come back because you
haven't learned your lesson yet?
何度やっても同じだ。
It's going to be the same,
no matter how many times you try.
お前に俺は倒せねえ。
You cannot beat me.
だな。
I know.
お前を無理やり倒そうとしても
うまくいかねえ。
Trying to defeat you
with force isn't going to work.
まったく同じ手
使ってくっからよ。
Because we use
the exact same moves.
俺を追い出そうとしてもムダだ。
You won't be able to
chase me out either.
お前のことは
俺が　いちばんよくわかってる。
I know you better than anyone else.
なら　もうお前だって
わかってるだろ？
Then...
You already know...
何が言いたい？
What do you want to say?
さっき決めたことさ。
What I decided earlier.
知るか　そんなもん。
I don't remember.
Don't act like you don't know.
しらばっくれんなよ。
まあ　いいや。
Well, never mind.
この場所は　自分の心の真実を
映す場所だから→
This place is supposed to show
the truth in your heart,
イメージを集中して
直接　お前に見せてやるよ。
so I'll concentrate on the image
and show it directly to you.
HOKAGE CANDIDATE #1 NARUTO
これが　俺のサインだ。
This is my autograph.
貴様！
Why you!
((あっ　そうだ　サインくれよ　サイン。
Oh hey! Give me
your autograph, Naruto!
うちの子に書いてやって
くんねぇかな？
Could you make it out to my kid?
He's a big fan of yours.
お前のファンでよ。
サイン？
An autograph?
The hero of the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉の英雄　奇跡を起こす少年
うずまきナルト。
The youth who created a miracle,
Naruto Uzumaki.
うちのほうにも１枚頼む。
Give me your autograph too!
どうした？　ダメか？
What is it? You refuse?
Oh no, but I'm not used to
that sort of thing.
いやぁ　俺ってば
そういうのに慣れてねえからよ→
I don't have a clue
what to sign.
(サインなんて持ってねえし))
あのとき　一楽で頼まれて
結局　書かなかったサインだ。
Back at Ichiraku, I couldn't give
them their autographs.
Here it is now.
そんなもん
作ったからといって何だ！？
Who cares if you have it now?
くだらねえ！
What a joke!
Everyone in the village is
just sweet-talking you.
里のヤツらにチヤホヤされて
騙されてるだけだ　お前は！
They don't mean it.
アイツらは　俺たちを
ずっと騙してきたヤツらだぞ！
They've been lying to us
the whole time.
勝手な掟を作って
のけ者にしてきた！
Making up rules and
treating us like outcasts!
思い出してみろ！
Don't you remember?
苦しかったよな…　辛かったよな。
It was so hard and painful.
お前を　わかってやれんのは
俺だけなんだぞ。
I'm the only one who will
ever understand you!
里のヤツらなんか信じるな！
Don't trust anyone
from the village!
ああ…。
Yeah...
里の人たちも大事だけど→
The villagers are important,
他に信じなきゃならないもんが
先にある。
but there's someone else
I have to trust first.
自分を信じてみようと思うんだ。
I have to believe in myself.
里のみんなに信頼されてる
自分っていうのをよ。
I need to trust the me that
the villagers believe in.
どうしてだ…。
Why?
あんなに…　あんなに
苦しまされてきたのに…。
After all that
they put us through?
タコのおっさんに気づかされた。
Octopops made me
realize something.
自分ってのを
まったく疑ってもねえ。
He doesn't doubt himself at all.
He has pride in himself.
自分に誇りを持ってる。
お前は…
お前は　俺が邪魔なのか？
Do you...
Do you consider me a burden?
なら　俺は　いったい
なんだったんだ！？
Just what am I to you?
お前がいたから
俺は強くなれた。
Because you existed,
I became strong.
お前のおかげで
ここまで来られた。
Thanks to you,
I've made it this far.
なら…　俺は…
俺は　どうすりゃいい！！
And?
And what am I...
And what am I
supposed to do now?
んなもん　簡単だろ。
That's simple.
お前は　俺になりゃいい。
You just become me.
お前も　俺なんだから。
Since you are me.
今まで　ありがとな。
Thanks for everything until today.
もう　いいんだ。
But it's going to be all right now.
♪～
ヘヘッ。
It seems...
どうやら…。
うまくいったんだね？
... it all went well?
It's too soon to celebrate,
fool, ya fool.
喜ぶのは　まだ早いぜ
バカ野郎　この野郎。
これから　九尾の力のコントロールを
やってみるか。
Shall we try to control
the Nine Tails' power now?
今から俺が　お前の師匠。
From this moment,
I'll be your instructor
覚悟を決めろ　でないと死傷。
Ya better prepare yourself or else
you'll suffer death n' torture.
よっしゃ！！
All right!
俺に　ついてこい　ナルト。
Come with me, Naruto!
あの…　僕も
ついていって　いいですか？
Um, may I come along?
オーケー。
Okay!
What about Motoi?
モトイさんは？
I have to report in to the Hidden Cloud
at regular intervals,
俺は　雲隠れへの
定時連絡があるので　このへんで。
so I'll take my leave here.
お疲れさまです。
Thank you for your help.
ここからは　簡単には
いかないだろうからな。
Things won't be easy
from here on out.
滝の向こうがあったのか。
So there was something on
the other side of the waterfall.
すげぇ…。
ここで　九尾と戦う。
Wow!
You'll fight the Nine Tails here!
九尾と戦う？
Fight the Nine Tails?
そうだ　バカ野郎　この野郎。
That's right, fool, ya fool.
うわっ！
これは　みごとですね。
This is amazing.
ついて来い。
Follow me.
古い遺跡のようですね。
These ruins seem to
be quite old.
考古学的にも貴重なようですし
修復が必要ですね。
They must have
archeological importance,
they should be restored.
No! Those stone statues were carved
without heads to begin with.
ノー。　その石像たちは初めから
首がないように造られている。
ある理由でな。
There's a reason for it.
こんなところで
九尾と戦うって→
How am I supposed to
fight the Nine Tails here?
どうやって戦うんだ？
What's more, how am I
supposed to face him?
そもそも
どうやって会うんだよ。
I hope you're not going to
do anything excessive!
まさか　ムチャなこと
するんじゃないでしょうね。
ムチャしないで
コントロールできると思うな。
Do you think it's something
that can be controlled
without doing
something excessive?
Fool, ya fool.
バカ野郎　コノ野郎。
ここは昔から人柱力に
選ばれた者が禊を行う→
Since long ago,
this has been a sacred place
where those selected as
Jinchuriki have come
to undergo
the Purification Ceremony.
神聖すぎる場所だ。
ここは尾獣と対話できる
システムになってる領域。
It's set up here so you can talk to
your Tailed Beast in a special way.
この建物の中だ　了解。
It's right inside this building.
You hear what I say?
ここが。
This is...
Only the chosen ones can enter...
To be selected.
ここへ入れるものは
選ばれたものだけ　選抜。
この石像の口の中へ
頭を入れろ　善人。
Go and stick your head
into the statue's mouth...
Like a good man, respected.
心の闇がなけりゃ　扉が開く　全開。
If there isn't any darkness
in your heart, the door will open...
Fully extended.
あの　なるべく
普通に説明してください。
Hey, can you explain it normally?
わかりにくくて…。
I don't quite understand.
No darkness in the heart?
心の闇がなけりゃって…。
そうか　だから滝で…。
I see, so that's why
at the waterfall...
ただし　もし少しでも
心の闇があれば→
However...
If there's even a little darkness
in your heart,
the gate will not part.
扉は開かない　承諾。
Do you consent?
どころか
首を石像に噛みちぎられる　承知。
And the statue will bite off
your head and tear you apart.
Are you content?
ここに来るときに見た
首のない石像は→
All the headless statues
you saw on your way here...
are past Jinchuriki who weren't...
sincere!
人柱力たちが　正体。
I'm your true self.
((つまり　俺はお前の真実だ。
(俺が本当のお前だ))
The real you.
リスクが大きすぎる。
This is too risky.
Naruto, use a Shadow Clone.
ナルト　影分身でやればいい。
ここは神聖な場所だ。
This is a sacred place,
fool, ya fool.
バカ野郎　コノ野郎。
雲隠れ代々の先代たちが
見守り見張っている。
Generations of Hidden Cloud
ancestors guard
and protect this place.
ごまかしは　きかない！
しかし…。
Tricks like that won't work!
But...
Captain Yamato...
ヤマト隊長…。
俺は九尾の力を
コントロールするために　ここに来た。
I came here to learn how
to control the Nine Tails' power!
これは
俺にとっても大切なことだ。
This is important to me.
I can't run away!
逃げらんねえ。
《自分を信じるんだってばよ》
I'm going to believe in myself!
うわ～っ！
ナルト！
Naruto!
そ　そんな…　なんてこった。
No! How could this happen!
ナルト　お前…。
Naruto!
You...
なんてね。
スイッチがあるだけでした。
Just kidding!
There's just a switch in there.
アハハハッ　お決まりだから　つい…。
It's a habit.
I couldn't help myself.
I did the same thing too.
Out of habit.
俺のときもやったぜ　常習。
Those stone statues are
just broken. It's just some wit.
石像は壊れてただけ　冗談。
I thought you said this place
was sacred! Fools, ya fools!
ここは神聖な場所じゃ
なかったんですか！
バカ野郎　コノ野郎。
This is...?
これって…。
この中へ入り
座って目を閉じ集中する。
Go inside,
close your eyes and focus.
滝のときと同じだ。
Just like at the waterfall.
Then you'll meet your Tailed Beast.
そうすれば
尾獣に会うことができる。
けど　俺ってば昔　修業して
心の中で　自分から→
Before when I was training,
I was able to meet
the Nine Tails in my mind.
九尾に会うことは
できるようになってんだけど。
それなら人柱力の
誰もがやってることだ。
Any Jinchuriki can do that.
ここはもう少し
別の意味もある　オーケー？
But this is
a little different, okay?
俺の話をよく聞け　説明。
Listen to me very carefully.
I'll give you an explanation.
ナルト　お前に封印した九尾の
封印術は　どんなんだ　切望。
Naruto, what kind of Sealing Jutsu
was used on your Nine Tails?
Please answer my question.
えっ？
四象封印です。
It's a Tetragram Seal.
四象封印か…。
立派なもんじゃねえか。
A Tetragram Seal, huh.
That's impressive.
俺様の鉄甲封印よりかたいな。
It's even more solid than
my Steel Shell Seal.
鍵は持ってんのか？
Do you have the key?
((ゲロ寅：大じじ様が言うなら
しゃあないわい。
I have no choice but to do
as you say, Great Lord Elder.
これって…。
What is this?
It is the key left by
the Fourth Hokage
四代目火影が残した→
(お前の腹の封印術を
開け閉めする鍵じゃ))
that locks and unlocks
the sealing jutsu on your belly!
うん。
やはり封印を解くんですね。
Yes!
You're going to undo
the seal, after all.
もしこのコントロールが
うまくいかなかったら…。
What if he can't
control it properly?
九尾が完全復活したら
どうするんです？
What if the Nine Tails
revives completely?
この場所に閉じ込め　封印する。
We'll seal him away here.
ここは　そういう場所でもある。
That's what this place
is for as well.
新しい人柱力を連れてくるまで
九尾はここに封印。
Until we get a new Jinchuriki,
this is where we'll seal him in.
いきなり早くもブーイング！
しかし…。
You got a problem with this?
No booin'.
– But...
– That won't happen!
そうはならねえ。
俺がやってみせっからよ。
Because I'm going to do this.
オーケー。　なら扉を閉めるぜ。
Okay! I'm going to shut the door.
これから
九尾とのやりとりを教える。
And I'll show you how to deal
with the Nine Tails!
ナルト　お前に感嘆　ルールは簡単。
Naruto, you really do impress me.
The rules are simple,
as you'll soon see.
精神の中で　九尾と挨拶したら
まず　封印を解け。
Greet the Nine Tails in
your subconscious mind,
then undo the seal.
Hey, evil glare as usual.
よう。
相変わらず　目つき　わりいな。
Naruto...
（九尾）ナルト！　キサマ…。
You...
なんだってばよ？
What is it?
本当のお前は　どこに行った？
感じないぞ。
Where'd the real you go?
I don't sense him.
ここに　いるだろ。
お前の目の前によ。
I'm here... right in front of you!
You conquered hatred.
（キラービー）お前は憎しみを克服した。
だが　安心するな　極力。
But don't relax,
do the best you can!
The Nine Tails is
a mass of true hatred.
九尾は
憎しみのかたまりだ　極論。
That's absolutely true, man!
どういうつもりだ？
What're you up to?
今　口がふさがってんだ。
見りゃ　わかんだろ。
Can't you see my mouth is full?
《いくぜ！》
Here I go...
♪～
When the Nine Tails emerges
from the seal,
（キラービー）九尾が封印から出たら→
grab the Nine Tails' chakra
with your own chakra,
自分のチャクラで
九尾のチャクラを捕まえて→
and pull it away!
引っぱり抜け！
《チャクラは　チャクラでしか
捕まえられねえ。　これ　常識。
Chakra can only be caught
with chakra.
It's common sense, son.
Take the Nine Tails' chakra
away from him...
九尾から　直接　九尾のチャクラを
奪えばいい。　それ　勝者》
and you'll be number one.
Touch the Nine Tails directly and
（キラービー）九尾に　直接　触れて→
stick your chakra onto its chakra,
and it'll pull each other.
自分のチャクラと九尾のチャクラを
くっつけたら　引き合いになる。
In other words, it's going to be
like a match of tug-of-war. Okay?!
要するに　綱引き勝負だ。　オーケー？
チッ！
I'll help you in your fight.
俺様も　戦いに参戦。
お前の精神の中だ。
But unfortunately inside
your head I got no might.
うまく力が出せるわけでもねえ。
残念。
He's strong!
やっぱ　つえぇな。
Just a word of warning.
（キラービー）言っとくが
チャクラを取ろうとするときは→
When you're trying to
take his chakra,
there's the risk that
he'll pull away yours.
逆に
引っぱり取られる危険もあるぜ。
こっちが　全部　抜き取られて
チャクラが　ゼロになったら→
I don't need to explain what'll
happen if all your chakra is
pulled away and
you have zero left, right?
どうなるか　説明はいらねえな？
I see. You intend to
control my power.
そうか…
わしの力を　コントロールする気だな？
八尾と組んだか。
So you teamed up
with Eight Tails?
You, the Jinchuriki of
the Nine Tails? That's pitiful!
九尾の人柱力とあろうものが
情けない！
（キラービー）確かに　リスクはでかい。
The risks are high for sure.
だが　ぶん取っちまえば→
But if you take it away,
the Nine Tails' chakra will
be yours forever!
九尾のチャクラは
一生　己のもんになる。
Grab whatever chakra you can
from the Nine Tails' will...
九尾の意志から　九尾のチャクラを
取れるだけ　ぶん取っちまえ！
That will be your payoff!
それが　褒美。
九尾の憎しみに　まどわされるな。
Don't get caught in
the Nine Tail's hatred.
Use your strong will.
強い自分の意志で　そいつを防備。
That's how you'll ward him off!
Don't underestimate me !
なめんな！
《サンキュー！　タコのおっさん》
Thank you, Octopops!
I managed to contain the explosion!
爆発は抑えた。
Naruto, that will be the last of
my cooperation to your operation!
強力な協力は　ここまでだ　ナルト。
《あぁ！
Thanks!
I'm sitting still
just as I thought.
座ったままだから
やっぱ　思ったとおり…》
仙法　超大玉螺旋丸！
Sage Art: Super Giant Rasengan!
いけ！
kotae nakute mo ii sa sagashi tsuzukeru n da yo
You don't have to answer, I'll keep on searching
sou otona ni naru jikan da ne
Yeah, I guess it's time to grow up
imasugu tsugetai kedo furue ga tomaranai
I want to tell you right now but I can't stop this shaking
kokoro wa ima sara nigete to sakebu no sa
My heart shouts for me to run away, even now
by my side by my side
By my side, By my side
tatoeba anata no me no oku ni
In the depth of your eyes, if there's a scenery you seek
motomeru keshiki ga aru no nara
sore wo tsukande tashikametai n da
I want to grasp it and see for myself
moshi kimi no namida ga kono sekai wo
If your tears have set you apart from this world
kimi kara toozaketa toshitemo
boku wa sono te hanasanai n da
I won't let go of your hand
dakara sou ima
So, yes... right now
i need you here right by my side
by my side
By my side
Next Episode
Damn it. The Nine Tails is no joke.
＜季節の鍋が大好きな豆助＞
If it weren't for him... I hate him.
What?
≫は～い　おまたせ
Don't give in Naruto! Fool, ya fool!
≫お鍋　できたわよ～
No one will ever respect someone like you!
What is this?
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "The Orange Spark"
＜　それは寒さ極まる　この季節→
The Orange Spark
Who are you?